# FIIWE BARISANEM

fiiwebarry@yahoo.com

08136719957

linkedin.com/in/barisanem-fiiwe-08659992

## **Summary**

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

A vibrant, inquisitive and well driven graduate of Babcock University, majoring in computer science, A meticulous web developer with over four years of front end development experience and passion for responsive website design and a firm believer in the mobile first approach. I have honed my skills in creating responsive and userfriendly websites using cutting-edge technologies like HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, cypress Test coverage and various frontend frameworks such as React and Vue.is.

#### CAREER OBJECTIVE:

Analytical-minded and creative team player with a strong background in designing ,planning and maintenance of software programs, desirous of a role of a Front-End Engineer to hone my technical skills and expertise along with designing creative software and products as per the clients' needs and enhance the reputation of your organisation.

## **Experience**



## Frontend Developer

#### KodeHauz

Feb 2024 - Present (2 months)

- I have made codes scalable, reuasable with the cypress Test coverage and componentization.
- Increasing the companies production and services to client by 40%
- · Created reusable front-end components and libraries to enhance development efficiency

## Frontend Developer(React.js)

iHealth and Wellness Foundation

Jun 2023 - Present (10 months)

I'm proud to be a frontend developer Volunteer at iHealth and Wellness Foundation, working on a project tha timproves patient outcomes for complex diseases through an online medical and wellness care platform.

- I collaborated with designers and back-end developers to implement website features and JavaScript functionalities
- I conducted thorough testing with vitest and cypress test coverage debugging to ensure cross-browser compatibility and optimal performance

## FRONT-END DEVELOPER (React.Js)

#### KodeCamp

Mar 2022 - Present (2 years 1 month)

• Designed and developed user interfaces for web applications using HTML, CSS,

and JavaScript (React.js)

- Created reusable front-end components and libraries to enhance development efficiency
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to gather requirements and deliver high-quality solutions
- Assisted in the design process by providing technical insights and feasibility analysis
- Conducted code reviews and provided constructive feedback to team members
- Stayed updated with the latest front-end technologies and trends

### FRONT-END DEVELOPER (Vue.Js)

#### WeDance

Mar 2021 - Mar 2022 (1 year 1 month)

- Developed and maintained responsive websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Collaborated with designers and back-end developers to implement website features and functionality
- Conducted thorough testing and debugging to ensure cross-browser compatibility and optimal performance
- Optimized website performance through efficient coding practices and image optimization techniques
- Worked closely with clients to understand their requirements and provide technical guidance
- Implemented SEO best practices to improve website visibility and search engine rankings

### FRONT-END DEVELOPER INTERN

### Media City Communications

Oct 2016 - Sep 2018 (2 years)

- I Implemented websites, mobile applications and Figma landing pages from concept through deployment
- Standardized all output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.
- · Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility
- Developed standard and ad hoc reports in graph format as required
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.

#### Key Achievements

- $\bullet$  Implemented new responsive, mobile-first approach which increased mobile traffic by 50%
- Rendering Quality services to client, building a strong relationship and a client base

#### **Education**

#### **Babcock University**

B.Sc, Computer Science 2011 - 2015 Second Class upper Division.

## **Skills**

React.js • HTML • Tailwind CSS • Bootstrap (Framework) • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • JavaScript • Next.js • Test Automation